Guide to the W. W. Morgan Papers circa 1905-1990
University of Chicago Library
Morgan, W. W. Papers
circa 1905-1990
58 linear feet (116 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
W. W. Morgan (1906-1994), astronomer. The papers document Morgan's career as a scientist and administrator at the Yerkes Observatory as well as his family history and personal interests. Contains correspondence, manuscripts, diaries, photographs and research materials
Information on Use
Access
Series X contains restricted budget, personnel and student materials. The remainder of the collection is open to research.
Biographical Note
William Wilson Morgan was born on January 3, 1906, in Bethesda, Tennessee. His father and his mother were both home missionaries in the Southern Methodist Church, and Morgan's childhood was spent moving around following his father's lecture itinerary. His basic education came from his parents. In 1923, Morgan entered Washington and Lee University in Lexington, Virginia. He was an excellent student in English and planned to become a teacher of literature. However, he was also a particularly good student in Physics and Mathematics. He impressed Professor of Physics and Astronomy Benjamin A. Wooten. Wooten had obtained a small, professional-quality refracting telescope for the university and Morgan soon began observing the sky.
In 1926, on Wooten's recommendation, Morgan started his graduate work at the Yerkes Observatory. Two years later he married Helen Barrett, daughter of astronomer Storrs B. Barrett, who was the secretary of the observatory. In June 1930, under the supervision of Otto Struve, he began a Ph.D. thesis on the spectra of A stars. Morgan completed his thesis and received his doctoral degree in December 1931. Despite the onset of the Great Depression and dark economic times, he was kept on the staff at Yerkes Observatory, though he remained in the same assistantship he had held as a graduate student. In the summer of 1932 he was promoted to instructor and in 1936 to assistant professor.
Morgan lived and worked at Yerkes Observatory for almost seventy years. An accomplished teacher and, for a period, editor of The Astrophysical Journal, Morgan's greatest achievements came from research. From the beginning of his work at Yerkes, Morgan's methods were grounded in the systematic organization of concrete data. Eschewing the then new field of theoretical astrophysics, he built his reputation as one of the greatest astronomers of the twentieth century with the morphological classification of stars based on stellar spectra. With Phillip Keenan and Edith Kellman, he created the MKK system for stellar classification, later refined to the MK system that remains in use today.
Morgan's work, though rigorous, was eclectic and improvisational, relying on his ability to wring significance from spectra that others could not interpret. In 1951, Morgan proved that the Milky Way Galaxy had spiral arms - a hypothesis proposed one hundred years before by Alexander. For this he received an unprecedented standing ovation from a meeting of the American Astronomical Society. His work was celebrated with many awards and honorary degrees, including membership in the Royal Danish Academy of Sciences and Letters and the Pontifical Academy of the Sciences.
In late 1951 or early 1952, Morgan suffered a nervous breakdown and was hospitalized for several months. Soon afterwards, he began to keep a journal recording his private thoughts and experiences. The collection contains almost 250 volumes of this journal, which Morgan wrote in regularly until 1990, when he seems to have begun to experience the effects of Alzheimer's Disease. In these journals, Morgan tries to psychoanalyze himself by following closely Freud's works as well as the works of other psychoanalysts and philosophers of the twentieth century. Also, the reader can find Morgan's own reflections, critiques and foundations to his corpus of work. For the astronomer the dividing line between science and art was blurry, and as proof of this he gives his own research.
In 1963, his wife Helen died. Morgan, his son and daughter, survived her. The emotional and professional implications for Morgan's life were devastating. In 1966, he married Jean Morgan, a teacher at the Rochester College in Chicago. He remained with Jean until his death in 1994. Jean strongly encouraged Morgan's artistic endeavors. In addition to his scientific work, Morgan never stopped taking photographs or writing about art in his journals. In one of his writings, Morgan states that his most important life works were his photography and journal. Morgan died in Chicago in 1994.
Scope Note
The bulk of the material dates from 1940 to 1990. Morgan was a prolific writer and photographer; his journal, correspondence and photographs make up the majority of the collection. He also preserved many of his notes and notebooks, as well as his star charts, star spectra, observation cards and astronomical tables and calculations. The divisions between the series are not strict and the subjects overlap in the series divisions. When possible the original folder names were preserved.
The papers have been divided into ten series: I. Journals, II. Correspondence, III. Research, IV. Symposia, Conferences and Workshops, V. Administration and Organizations, VI. Teaching and Counseling, VII. General, VIII. Photography, IX. Oversize, and X. Restricted.
Related Resources
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Morgan, W. W. (William Wilson), 1906-; Yerkes Observatory; Astronomy; Astronomers; Photographs
INVENTORY
- Series I: Personal Journals
  The series contains more than 250 notebooks. For more than thirty years Morgan wrote regularly, on average, between three or four times a week. The notebooks are in excellent condition and usually contain newspaper clippings, notes, and photographs related to the writings. The main objective of the diary was to provide Morgan with a self-counsel, a kind of self psychoanalysis. Nonetheless, the journal contains numerous entries in which the author relates different astronomical problems, his research concerns, and his research methods. The journals are also rich in artwork, as well as movie and book reviews, and philosophical musings.
  - Vol. 3, April 20 - Oct. 31, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 4, Oct. 31, 1955 - Jan. 10, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 6, Mar. 12 - Apr. 15, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 7, Apr. 15 - May 10, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 8, May 10 - June 8, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 9, June 8 - July 8, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 10, July 8 - Aug. 29, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 11, Aug. 30 - Sept. 27, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 12, Sept. 27 - Nov. 6, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 13, Nov. 7 - Dec. 1, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 14, Dec. 1-18, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 15, Dec. 19, 1956 - Jan. 17, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 16, Jan. 3-4, 18 - Feb. 25, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 17, Feb. 25 - Mar. 25, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 18, Mar. 25 - Apr. 21, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 20, June 15 - July 17, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 21, July 17 - Aug. 7, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 22, Aug. 9 - Sept. 22, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 23, Sept. 22 - Nov. 5, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 24, Nov. 5, 1957 - Jan. 19, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 25, Jan. 19 - Feb. 28, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 26, Feb. 28 - Mar. 13, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 27, Mar. 14-24, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 28, Mar. 25 - Apr. 17, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 29, Apr. 17-29, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 30, Apr. 30 - May 19, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 31, May 19-31, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 32, May 31 - June 15, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 33, June 15-22, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 34, June 22 - July 10, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 35, July 10-16, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 36, July 17-28, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 37, Aug. 9 - Sept. 11, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 38, Sept. 11-28, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 39, Sept. 28 - Oct. 10, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 40, Oct. 10 - Nov. 2, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 41, Nov. 2-30, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 42, Nov. 30 - Dec. 27, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 43, Dec. 28, 1958 - Jan. 22, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 44, Jan. 22 - Feb. 8, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 45, Feb. 9 - Mar. 1, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 46, Mar. 1-15, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 49, May 26 - July 11, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 50, July 11 - Aug. 25, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 51, Aug. 25 - Oct. 18, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 52, Oct. 19 - Nov. 4, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 53, Nov. 4 - Dec. 11, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 54, Dec. 11, 1959 - Jan. 9, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 55, Jan. 9-25, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 56, Jan. 26 - Feb. 17, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 57, Feb. 17 - Mar. 7, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 58, Mar. 7-25, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 59, Mar. 25 - Apr. 11, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 60, Apr. 12 - May 11, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 61, May 12 - June 18, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 62, June 18 - July 11, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 63, July 11 - Aug. 6, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 64, Aug. 6 - Sept. 3, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 65, Sept. 3-23, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 66, Sept. 23 - Oct. 19, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 67, Oct. 19 - Nov. 12, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 68, Nov. 13-30, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 69, Dec. 1-21, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 70, Dec. 19, 1960 - Jan. 16, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 71, Jan. 13 - Feb. 1, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 72, Feb. 2-21, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 73, Feb. 21 - Mar. 13, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 74, Mar. 13-31, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 75, Apr. 1-18, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 76, Apr. 19 - May 7, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 77, May 8-28, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 78, May 29 - June 22, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 79, June 22 - July 14, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 80, July 15 - Aug. 7, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 81, Aug. 8 - Sept. 9, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 82, Sept. 9 - Oct. 4, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 83, Oct. 5 - Nov. 5, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 84, Nov. 5 - Nov. 30, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 85, Nov. 30 - Dec. 31, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 86, Jan. 1 - Jan. 31, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 87, Jan. 31 - Feb. 26, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 88, Feb. 27 - Apr. 2, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 89, Apr. 3 - May 21, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 90, May 21 - June 20, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 91, June 21 - July 14, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 92, July 15 - Aug. 5, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 93, Aug. 5 - Sept. 14, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 94, Sept. 15 - Sept. 30, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 95, Oct. 1-25, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 96, Oct. 25 - Nov. 29, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 97, Nov. 30 - Dec. 17, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 98, Dec. 17, 1962 - Jan. 1, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 99, Jan. 2-26, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 100, Jan 26 - Feb. 20, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 101, Feb. 21 - Mar. 24, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 102, Mar. 25 - May 1, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 103, May 3 - June 1, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 104, June 2-30, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 105, June 30 - July 31, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 106, Aug. 1 - Aug. 19, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 107, Aug. 20 - Sept. 22, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 108, Sept. 22 - Oct. 23, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 109, Oct. 24 - Nov. 28, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 110, Nov. 29, 1963 - Jan. 11, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 111, Jan. 11 - Jan. 26, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 112, Jan. 27 - Feb. 15, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 113, Feb. 15 - Feb. 26, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 114, Feb. 27 - Mar. 14, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 115, Mar. 14 - Mar. 30, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 116, Mar. 30 - Apr. 21, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 117, Apr. 21 - May 27, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 118, May 28 - July 10, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 119, July 11 - Aug. 16, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 120, Aug. 17 - Sept. 10, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 121, Sept. 10 - Oct. 13, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 122, Oct. 14 - Nov. 10, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 123, Nov. 10 - Dec. 9, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 124, Dec. 9, 1964 - Jan. 12, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 125, Jan. 12 - Feb. 13, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 126, Feb. 13 - Mar. 14, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 127, Mar. 14 - Apr. 10, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 128, Apr. 11 - May 31, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 129, June 1 - July 19, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 130, July 20 - Sept. 3, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 131, Sept. 4 - Oct. 16, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 132, Oct. 16 - Nov. 14, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 133, Nov. 15, 1965 - Jan. 1, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 134, Jan. 2 - Mar. 17, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 135, Mar. 18 - May 23, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 136, May 23 - June 25, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 137, June 25 - Aug. 8, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 138, Aug. 8 - Sept. 25, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 139, Sept. 25 - Oct. 20, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 140, Oct. 20 - Nov. 20, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 141, Nov. 21 - Dec. 31, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 142, Dec. 31, 1966 - Feb. 17, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 143, Feb. 18 - Apr. 5, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 144, Apr. 6 - May 1, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 145, May 2 - July 6, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 146, July 6 - Sept. 2, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 147, Sept. 3 - Oct. 24, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 148, Oct. 24 - Dec. 17, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 149, Dec. 17, 1967 - Jan. 21, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 150, Jan. 22 - Mar. 4, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 151, Mar. 4 - Apr. 5, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 152, Apr. 7 - May 29, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 153, May 29 - July 24, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 154, July 25 - Sept. 24, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 155, Sept. 24 - Oct. 26, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 156, Oct. 26 - Dec. 13, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 157, Dec. 14, 1968 - Feb. 10, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 158, Feb. 10 - Mar. 7, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 159, Mar. 8 - Apr. 30, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 160, May 1 - June 1, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 161, June 1 - July 5, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 162, July 5 - Sept. 3, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 163, Sept. 3 - Oct. 18, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 164, Oct. 19 - Dec. 26, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 165, Dec. 26, 1969 - Feb. 18, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 166, Feb. 19 - Mar. 21, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 167, Mar. 21 - Apr. 20, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 168, Apr. 21 - June 18, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 169, June 20 - Aug. 9, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 170, Aug. 9 - Sept. 3, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 171, Sept. 3-30, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 172, Oct. 1-30, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 173, Oct. 30 - Dec. 20, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 174, Dec. 20, 1970 - Feb. 4, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 175, Feb. 4 - Mar. 24, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 176, Mar. 25 - May 1, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 177, May 2 - June 6, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 178, June 7 - July 29, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 179, Aug. 1 - Sept. 22, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 180, Sept. 23 - Nov. 29, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 181, Nov. 29, 1971 - Jan. 20, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 182, Jan. 21 - Mar. 3, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 183, Mar. 3 - Apr. 17, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 184, Apr. 17 - June 2, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 185, June 3 - July 29, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 186, July 30 - Sept. 20, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 187, Sept. 21 - Nov. 15, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 188, Nov. 16, 1972 - Jan. 15, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 189, Jan. 17 - May 15, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 190, May 16 - July 18, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 191, July 22 - Oct. 6, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 192, Oct. 7, 1973 - Jan. 4, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 193, Jan. 4 - Mar. 26, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 194, Mar. 26 - May 22, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 195, May 24 - June 30, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 196, June 30 - Sept. 29, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 197, Sept. 30 - Dec. 1, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 198, Dec. 2, 1974 - Feb. 21, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 199, Feb. 20 - May 8, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 200, May 8 - Sept. 26, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 201, Sept. 28 - Dec. 29, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 202, Dec. 31, 1975 - Mar. 19, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 203, Mar. 24 - June 5, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 204, June 6 - Aug. 13, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 205, Aug. 13 - Oct. 8, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 206, Oct. 9, 1976 - Jan. 30, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 207, Jan. 31 - June 3, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 208, June 4 - Oct. 12, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 209, Oct. 13, 1977 - Jan. 15, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 210, Jan. 20 - Apr. 16, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 211, Apr. 18 - Aug. 6, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 212, Aug. 6 - Nov. 25, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 213, Nov. 26 - Dec. 8, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 214, Dec. 9, 1978 - Mar. 27, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 215, Mar. 27 - July 15, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 216, July 17, 1979 - Jan. 28, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 216-S (Supplement), undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 217, Jan. 28 - May 29, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 218, May 30 - Sept. 19, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 219, Sept. 18 - Feb. 2, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 20, Feb. 6 - June 10, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 221, June 16 - Nov. 10, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 222, Nov. 15, 1981 - Mar. 22, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 223, Mar. 22 - Apr. 24, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 224, Apr. 27 - May 7, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 225, May 7/8-20, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 226, May 27 - Sept. 25, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 227, Oct. 10, 1982 - Feb. 14, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 228, Feb. 16 - May 26, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 229, May 29 - Aug. 2, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 230, Aug. 3 - Nov. 30, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 231, Dec. 1, 1983 - Mar. 31, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 232, Mar. 31 - June 27, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 233, June 28 - July 27, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 234, July 29 - Oct. 20, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 235-A, Oct. 21-Nov. 4, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 235-B, Oct. 1984 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 235-C, Nov. 13, 1984 - Jan. 28, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 236, Feb. 1 - May 28, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 237, May 28 - Sept., 1985 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 238, Sept. 23, 1985 - Jan. 10, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 239, Jan. 12 - June 23, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 240, May 12, 1986 - Jan. 14, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 240-A, July 10, 1986 - Jan. 21, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 241, Jan. 25 - Apr. 14, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 244, Jan. 25 - Nov. 18, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 244-A, Jan. 8-21, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 245, Oct. 21, 1988 - Apr. 21, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 246, May 22, 1989 - Jan. 16, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 247, Mar. 26 - Sept. 11, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Addressed Journal with Pages Torn Out, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Diary, 1925 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Diary, 1946 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - "Expense Statements and Notes, Rome Trip," May-June, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Journal, 1928-1929 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Journal, 1942-1943 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Journal 199, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, July 1958 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - "Paul - Merton," 1975 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - "Picture Lady," 1981-1986 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - "The Christian Today," 1979 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - "The Parables of Jesus," 1978-1979 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Unlabeled Journal, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - "X-Mas Cards," 1982-1983 (Box 26, Folder 9)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1932-1937 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1936 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1953 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1944-1948 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1947-1960 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1948-1952 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1976 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1973 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1988 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1989 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1989 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1992 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - 1987-1988 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - 1988-1989 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - 1992-1993 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Abt Helmut A., Correspondence, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Abt Helmut A., The Astrophysical Journal, 1974-1981 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Abt Helmut A., Folder 1, 1978-1980 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Abt Helmut A., Folder 2, 1978-1980 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Adams Thomas F., 1975-1982 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Acknowledgement of Atlas (Letters), 1979 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Astronomy and Astrophysics: A European Journal, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - The Astronomical Journal, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - The Astrophysical Journal, 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - A-B-C, 1952-1953 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - A-L, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Babcock H.W., 1976 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Blaauw Correspondence, 1948-1952 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Blaauw Correspondence, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Bless Robert C., 1982 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Britannica Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Burbidge Geoffrey, 1975-1983 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Burbidge Geoffrey Birthday, 1985 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Burbidge Geoffrey Birthday Correspondence, 1985 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Burbidge E. Margaret, 1981-1982 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Business Correspondence, 1937 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Business Correspondence, 1966 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Carbons of Letters Regarding Atlas, 1978-1980 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Cards and Messages, Folder 1, 1963-1973 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Cards and Messages, Folder 2, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Cards and Messages, Folder 3, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Cards and Messages, Folder 4, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Cards and Messages, Folder 5, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Chalonge Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Christmas Cards, Folder 1, 1967-1969 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Christmas Cards, Folder 2, 1967-1969 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Christmas Cards, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Cowley Anne P., 1976-1982 (Box 32, Folder 8)